# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

# **NGUYEN THANH HUYNH**

Address: Sky9 department, Dis 9, HCM

Tel: +84984883750

Email: huynh2102@gmail.com

My portfolio: https://brianhuynh2021.github.io/brianhuynh\_porfolio/



#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I specialize in backend development with a focus on Django and have experience working in AGILE/Scrum environments. I'm skilled in system analysis, design, architecture development, testing, and debugging. Additionally, I can collaborate effectively with frontend teams, particularly with Nextjs

## **WORKING EXPERIENCES**

- April 2024 to current: Python Developer

Company: Bstar Solutions CT Building, 56 Yên Thế, Phường 2, Tân Bình, Hồ Chí Minh Project: Al chatbot - onsite working for a bank.

- API Development: Designed and implemented RESTful APIs using FastAPI to handle data extraction, data embedding, and integration with PostgreSQL and Milvus vector database.
- Data Processing: Created pipelines to extract data, train embeddings, and store them in a vector database for efficient similarity search.
- Cloud Integration: Deployed solutions on AWS, utilizing S3 for file storage and API Gateway for secure API management.
- Chatbot Service: Built a WebSocket-based chatbot service that efficiently responds to customer inquiries in real-time.
- Risk Analysis: Developed a system to analyze risky transactions and detect suspicious behavior in user accounts using data insights and anomaly detection techniques.
- Technologies: FastAPI, PostgreSQL, Milvus, AWS (S3, API Gateway), Claud3, chatGPT APIs, WebSocket, Python, Next.js, telegram chatBot notification.

## - Sept 2022 to Feb 2024: Python developer

Company: Datafluct Company <a href="https://datafluct-international.com/">https://datafluct-international.com/</a>

Project: Data ETL Platform.

- Maintain, design, and develop Backend REST API Web service based on Django frameworks
- Extract/Design database by PostgreSQL/MySQL for updating and developing system.

- Collaborate with FE Vue.js to deliver/deploy tasks or directly find out which issue came from FE, and fix it as if it is a minor bug.
- Config and migrate existing codebases to AWS/GCP, working with S3 bucket.

Sept 2020 to May 2023: Python developer

Company: FPT Software Vietnam

Project: Healthcare Service

Healthcare marketing and medical practice management solution platform enhancing the connection between patients and clinics.

- Maintain and develop Backend REST API/fastAPI Web service based on Flask/Django frameworks.
- Config and migrate existing Codebases to AWS using serverless Cloudformation.
- Verify, extract, and create database SQL for updating and developing system database.
- Using GraphQL showing expected data base on requirement for the API.

**July 2018 to July 2020:** Quality Data Analyst, Teleperformance, Penang Island, Malaysia.

- Responsible for coaching agents, monitoring agents' tasks daily, and doing audits based on report system by tracking CSV, SQL files.
- Cleansing raw data, analyzing, and visualizing insights of data by chart, dashboard using Python pandas, matplotlib, NumPy libraries.
- Problem-solving skill, Analysis skills, time management skill, understanding of SLAs and ability to coordinate and work with geographically separate sites.

**October 2016 – March 2018**: Technical support consultant, Officience Company, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam: Technical Support

- Receive third-party user calls and log issues, emails following standard ticket classification and call answering procedures.
- Monitor and comply with standard SLAs agreed with customers; Escalate serious issues to direct manager and customer.
- Access remotely to customer network monitoring platform.

**2015 – September 2016**: Customer Technical Support, Dell Company, Bayan Lepas Industrial Zone, Penang Island, Malaysia.

- Support customers with technical issues: software and hardware.
- Technical support the system and devices by troubleshooting issues from the end user and providing immediate solutions.

- Working knowledge of all software, drivers, systems of PCs, laptops, storage peripheral devices (mouse, wireless, keyboard, HDD).

#### **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

- September 2010 October 2013: University of Science.
- College of Information Technology and Engineering.
- Diploma of Science in Computer Science.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## Languages:

- HTML, CSS
- Javascript (knowledge of Vuejs, NextJS)
- Golang
- Django Python (main skill), flask, fastAPI
- SQL (PostgreSQL, MySQL), Redis

## **Tools, Frameworks, and Libraries:**

- Git and GitHub, CI/CD pipeline
- Django/Flask
- Alembic, SQLAlchemy, Pydantic
- Bootstrap
- Linux / Windows
- VSCode

# Cloud Service knowledge:

- AWS (S3, APIgateway)

#### Testing:

- Knowledge of TDD, BDD

# **OTHER SKILLS**

- Fluent in English (verbal & non-verbal).
- Logical and critical thinking for problem solving, time management skills.